Carl W. Ackerman Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Subject File, 1908-1970 (Box 34-158)
  - National Press Club, Washington
  - National Industrial Recovery Act, National Recovery Administration See Containers 73, -74 76 -79
  - National Sponsoring Committee, 1923
  - New York Herald Tribune, 1963, 1966
    - Lindsay, John V.
    - Whitney, John Hay
  - New York Standard, 1963
  - New York State Legislative Correspondents Alumni Association, 1960-1966
  - New York State Newspaper National Defense Committee, 1941
  - New York State Society of Newspaper Editors, 1939, 1956-1963
  - New York Times, 1917-1967 (Box 122)
    - Correspondence
      - Grasty, Charles H.
      - James, Edwin L.
      - Ochs, Adolph S.
      - Selden, Charles A.
      - Van Anda, Carr V.
      - Wiley, Louis
    - Expense accounts, Siberia, Oct. 1918-Feb. 1919
    - Letters of introduction, cards, Siberia, 1918-1919
  - New York Tribune, Garet Garrett, 1917
  - New York World's Fair, New York, N.Y., 1939
  - Newsweek, 1963
  - Nicholson, Ralph
    - Autobiography
    - Miscellany
  - Niebuhr, Walter, 1917
  - Northwestern University, Evanston, Ill., 1934-1935
  - Noyes, Pierrepont B., 1923
  - Oberlaender Trust (Carl Schurz Memorial Foundation, Inc.) (Box 123)
    - Mar. 1931-June 1932
      - Oberlaender, Gustave
      - Thomas, Wilbur K.
    - July 1932-Dec. 1933 (Box 124)
    - Jan. 1934-Dec. 1935 (Box 125)
    - Jan. 1936-Dec. 1937 (Box 126)
    - Jan. 1938-June 1939 (Box 127)
    - July 1939-Dec. 1940 (Box 128)
    - 1941, 1946, 1952-1953, 1956, undated (Box 129)
  - Overseas Press Club of America, Inc., 1940-1959
  - Pan American Union, 1917
  - Panama, trip, Jan. 1964
  - Pegler, Westbrook, 1948-1956
  - Pep, 1918-1919
  - Philadelphia Public Ledger, 1917-1919, and Philadelphia Public Ledger Foreign News Service, 1920-1921 (Box 130)
    - Bretherton, Cyril H.
    - Carew, F. H.
    - Clippings, miscellaneous
    - Conger, Seymour Beach
    - Curtis, Cyrus H. K.
    - Emanuel, Guglielmo
    - Expense accounts, miscellaneous
    - Foreign correspondents, lists
    - House, Edward Mandell
    - Kospoth, B. F.
    - Lee, Morris
    - Letters of introduction
    - Martin, John C.
    - Memoranda, London, 1920-1921
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, London, England (Box 131)
    - News dispatches, miscellaneous
    - Nicholson, Ralph
    - Pilcher, George
    - Printed matter (advertisements)
    - Smiley, David E.
    - Spurgeon, John J.
      - 1919-1920
      - Jan.-July 1921, undated (Box 132)
    - Streit, Clarence K.
      - Correspondence
      - Dispatches
      - Expense accounts
    - Stuart, John M.
    - Thatcher, Sidney L.
    - Tour of the United States, 1919
    - Tyler, Charles A.
    - Watkins, John Elfreth (Box 133)
    - Williams, Wythe
  - Phillips Memorial Hospital, Lambertville, N.J.
  - Poland, embassy, Washington, D.C.
  - La Prensa, 1951
  - Princeton University, Princeton, N.J.
  - Publicity file, printed matter
    - 1923-1925
    - 1926-1937, undated (Box 134)
  - Puerto Rico, trip, 1952
  - Puerto Rico, University of, proposed school of journalism, 1952-1953, undated
  - Pulitzer, Joseph, centennial, 1947
  - Pulitzer, Joseph, centennial, 1947 (Box 135)
    - Correspondence and clipping book
  - Pulitzer Prize
    - Advisory Board correspondence and memoranda
      - 1932-1942
        - Butler, Nicholas Murray
        - Cooper, Kent
        - Fackenthal, Frank D.
        - Finley, John H.
        - Harris, Julian LaRose
        - James, Edwin L.
        - Krock, Robert
        - Lathan, Robert
        - Pulitzer, Joseph (1885-1955)
        - Pulitzer, Ralph
        - White, William Allen
      - 1943-1954 (Box 136)
        - Choate, Robert
        - Cooper, Kent
        - Fackenthal, Frank D.
        - Kent, Frank
        - Krock, Arthur
        - Perry, Stuart H.
        - Pulitzer, Joseph (1885-1955)
        - White, William Allen
      - Typescripts, 1921-1956, undated
        - Firkins, O. W.
        - Frost, Robert
        - Lewis, Sinclair
        - Marsh, Margaret Mitchell
        - Nevins, Allan
        - Pegler, Westbrook
        - Rawlings, Marjorie Kinnan
        - Saroyan, William
    - Award winners, correspondence
      - Lippmann, Walter
      - Price, Byron
    - 50th anniversary, 1966
    - Miscellany
    - Nevins, Allan, Grover Cleveland
    - Printed matter (Box 137)
      - 1933-1946
      - 1947-1956 (Box 138)
  - The Quaker, 1921
  - Quezon, Manuel L., luncheon in honor of, 1937
  - Rand, James H., Jr., 1927
  - Religion
  - Research Corp.
  - Retirement at age sixty-five, practice of, 1955-1958
    - Bowman, Karl M.
    - Lee, Maurice du Pont
  - Richmond, University of, Richmond, Va., 1935
  - Russia, miscellany, 1914-1921, 1959, undated (Box 139)
  - Russian Information Bureau in the United States, 1919
  - St. John's Church, Washington, C. Leslie Glenn
  - St. Louis Post-Dispatch, Joseph Pulitzer
  - San Marcos de Lima, Universidad Mayor de
  - Saturday Evening Post, George Horace Lorimer, 1917-1933, undated (Box 140)
  - Sayre, Monell, 1923
  - Science Service, Watson Davis, 1931, 1937-1938
  - Scribner's (Charles) Sons, 1919
  - Scripps-Howard newspapers, John H. Sorrells, 1948
  - Seiberling Rubber Co., F. A. Seiberling, 1926-1930
  - Siberia, 1918-1919, 1931
    - Czecho-Slovak National Committee in Siberia, 1918-1919
    - Graves, William S., 1931
    - Miscellaneous correspondence
    - Miscellany
    - Notes, memoranda, fragments (Box 141)
    - Robinson, O. P.
    - United States Department of State, memoranda for
  - Sidener and Van Riper, Indianapolis, Ind., 1911-1912, 1959
  - Sigma Delta Chi, 1922-1963 (Box 142)
  - Society of the Silurians, Inc.
  - Sons of Indiana, 1957
  - Spier, Lester, 1960
  - Stagg, Jerry, 1963
  - Steffanson, Haakon B.
  - Stevenson, Adlai E. (1900-1964), presidential campaign, correspondence and clipping book, 1952 (Box 143)
  - Streit, Clarence K., 1944-1956
  - Switzerland
    - Correspondence and memoranda, 1918
    - Miscellany, 1917-1918 (Box 144)
  - Time magazine, Henry R. Luce
  - The Times (London), Stanley Morison
  - Tong, Hollington K., 1957
  - Trinity Church, New York, N.Y.
    - Correspondence, 1938-1969
      - Fleming, Frederic S.
      - Heuss, John
    - Printed matter
  - United Press (Box 145)
  - United Press Associations., 1913-1917, 1934, 1940
    - Correspondence
      - Hawkins, William W.
      - Howard, Roy Wilson
    - Printed matter
  - United Press International
  - United States Brewers Association
    - Advertising Review Panel
      - 1955
      - 1956-1960 (Box 146)
      - 1960-1963 (Box 147)
      - 1963-1966 (Box 148)
      - 1966-Sept. 1968 (Box 149)
      - Oct. 1968-1970 and miscellaneous (Box 150)
  - United States Department of Justice, Tom C. Clark, 1946-1948 (Box 151)
  - United States Department of State, 1917-1918, 1945-1948
    - Correspondence
      - Bliss, Robert Woods
      - Lovett, Robert A.
    - International Information Program, 1945-1946
      - Benton, William
    - Voice of America, 1947-1948
  - United States Office of Censorship, Bryon Price, 1941-1945
  - University Club, New York, N.Y., 963-1969
  - Unwin (T. Fisher) Ltd., 1917
  - Venezuela, Central University of, 1947, 1955-1956 (Box 152)
    - Bauman, Everett
    - Cardenas, Horacio
    - Jimenez, Marcos Perez
  - Venezuela, Social Service Commission to, 1939
    - Drought, James
  - Venezuela, trip, 1947
    - Scrapbook
      - Vol. 1, Apr.-July 1947
      - Vol. 2. Sept.-Dec. 1947 (Box 153)
      - 1948 (Box 154)
    - Miscellany, 1947-1948, 1954
  - Von Wiegand, Karl H.
  - Wagner, Robert F., 1953, 1963
  - War Department, Bureau of Public Relations, Robert C. Richardson, Jr., 1941
  - Washington Cathedral, Washington, D.C., 1923-1963, undated
    - Bratenahl, G. G.
    - Freeman, James E.
    - Lewis, Edwin N.
    - Rhinelander, Philip M.
    - Miscellany
    - Printed matter, 1919-1957, undated (Box 155)
  - Washington Post, Eugene Meyer, 1934-1956
  - White House Correspondents Association, 1938, 1964
  - Willkie, Wendell
  - World trip, 1935-1936
    - Clippings concerning Ackerman
    - Itinerary
    - Correspondence and clipping book (Box 156)
    - Miscellany
  - World War I (Box 157)
    - Miscellany
    - Miscellany (Box 158)
    - Notebook, circa 1918
    - Scrapbook
      - Washington, D.C., 1914
      - Berlin, Germany, 1915-1916
- Speech, Article, and Book File, 1909-1964 (Box 159-193)
  Handwritten and typewritten drafts, proofs, printed copies, notes, research material, and correspondence relating to speeches, articles, books, reports, and miscellaneous writings by Ackerman.
  Arranged by type of material and chronologically within each file. A partial list of correspondents is provided for some files.
  - Speeches (Box 159)
    - "Progress in Journalism," Ionian Literary Society, Earlham College, Richmond, Ind., 12 Nov. 1909
    - "The Causes of the Present Industrial Unrest," National Hardware Association of the United States, 16 Oct. 1919
    - "Dawes' Prosperity Plan," American Hardware Manufacturers' Association, 16 Oct. 1924
    - "Do It in the United States of America," American Hardware Manufacturers' Association, 16 Oct. 1924
    - "Journalism in the 'Machine Age,'" annual chapel service, School of Journalism, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 16 May 1930
    - Remarks, School of Journalism dinner for John W. Cunliffe, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 29 Apr. 1931
    - Talk to Copyreaders' Club, New York Herald Tribune, 30 Apr. 1931
    - Chapel talk, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 14 May 1931
    - "The Growth of Journalism," School of Journalism, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 26 Sept. 1931
    - "Co-operative Advertising," Advertising Club of New York, News York, N.Y., 28 Oct. 1931
    - "Life Is Action," Riverside Church, New York, N.Y., 2 Feb. 1932
      - Eastman, George, correspondence
    - Address at convention of Inter-Collegiate News Association, Haverford College, Haverford, Pa., 16 Apr. 1932
    - NBC Broadcast on anniversary of the founding of the Boston News Letter, 24 Apr. 1932
    - "The Relationship of Discipline and Control to Education," 18 May 1932
    - "The Newspaper in Public Affairs," Advertising Federation of America, 21 June 1932
    - Introduction of John H. Finley, 14 Nov. 1932
    - "Balancing the Newspaper Budget," Institute of Citizenship and Georgia Press Institute, Emory University, Atlanta, Ga., 10 Feb. 1933
    - "The Newspaper in International Affairs," Institute of Citizenship and Georgia Press Institute, Emory University, Atlanta, Ga., 10 Feb. 1933
    - "Challenge to the Press," American Society of Newspaper Editors, Washington, D.C., 29 Apr. 1933
    - "The Press of Today," University of Missouri, Columbia, Mo., 2 May 1933
    - Chapel talk, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 19 May 1933
    - "The Last Proving Ground for Democracy," Commercial Club of Chicago, Chicago, Ill., 24 Nov. 1933
    - "The Philosophy of Journalism," Yale University, New Haven, Conn., 8 Jan. 1934
    - "The Leadership of the Press," New York State Publishers Association, 12 Jan. 1934
    - "The Recovery of Youth," New York State Newspaper Publishers' Association, 17 Jan. 1934
    - Address, Ohio Newspaper Association, 9 Feb. 1934
    - "Liberty and Living," Brotherhood of St. Andrew, Cathedral of St. John the Divine, New York, N.Y., 22 Feb. 1934
    - "A New Approach to Peace," NBC broadcast, 23 Feb. 1934
      - Correspondence, George Seldes
    - "The Treaty of Peace with the Press," New York Conference of Business Paper Editors, New York, N.Y., 28 Feb. 1934 (Box 160)
    - "Journalism in World Affairs," Association of Foreign Press Correspondents, 19 Apr. 1934
    - Remarks at dinner for Pulitzer Prize winners, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 7 May 1934
    - "More Freedom for Business," City Club of Portland, Portland, Oreg., 20 July 1934
    - "Freedom of Opinion Makes Public Opinion," California Newspaper Publishers Association., 3 Aug. 1934
    - "The Church and the Press," Annual conference for clergy of the New York Diocese, Lake Mahopac, N.Y., 3 Oct. 1934
    - "Press Radio, an Experiment in Public Service," NBC broadcast, 19 Dec. 1934
    - "Intellectual Endowments in International Education," Alumni Day, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 12 Feb. 1935
    - "Education and Society," chapel service, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 13 May 1935
    - Remarks at luncheon given by George B. Dryden in honor of Ackerman, Chicago Club, Chicago, Ill., 14 June 1935
    - "The Test of Citizenship," National Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs, Seattle, Wash., 16 July 1935
    - "The Press," roundtable conference on "The Press and Crime Prevention," 2 Oct. 1935
    - "Invest in Youth," 1935
    - Miscellaneous lecture notes, world trip, Oct. 1935-Jan. 1936
    - "Freedom of the Press," Sorbonne, Paris, France, 7 Jan. 1936
    - "The Press in World Affairs,"Sorbonne, Paris, announcements, clippings, 14 Jan. 1936
    - "The Source of Our Liberties," Advertising Bureau of the American Newspaper Publishers' Association, 23 Apr. 1936
    - Speech, American Society of Newspaper Editors, Apr. 1936
    - "Leadership in a Democracy," Earlham College, Richmond, Ind., 15 June 1936
    - "The Freedom to Advance Knowledge," Faculty Club of Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 8 Oct. 1936
    - Remarks, memorial service for Marlen Pew, 18 Nov. 1936
    - "Workshops for Public Opinion," Newspaper Institute, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, N.C., 15 Jan. 1937
    - Father-and-son dinner, Columbia College, 12 Feb. 1937
    - "The Doctor and Public Opinion," Medical Society of the State of New York, Rochester, N.Y., correspondence, 25 May 1937
    - "The Role of the Press as a Factor in Public Opinion and Economic Change," National Industrial Conference Board, 27 May 1937
    - Address at University of LaPlata, Argentina, 25 Aug. 1937 (Box 161)
    - "The Newspaper Guild," New York Herald Tribune Forum, 4 Oct. 1937
    - "Is a Constitutional Amendment the Price of Peace?" First Presbyterian Church, Buffalo, N.Y., correspondence, 20 Mar. 1938
    - "Editors, to Arms," American Society of Newspaper Editors, Washington, D.C., 22 Apr. 1938
    - "The Leadership of the Pope," Saint Mary's College, Notre Dame, Ind., 4 June 1938
    - "The American Axis," University of Nebraska, Lincoln, Neb., correspondence, Brett Homer, 6 June 1938
    - "Receptivity, the Key to the Universe," Graduate School of Journalism, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 29 Sept. 1938
    - "The Central Problem of Democracy," National Conference on Government, National Municipal League, Baltimore, Md., 1 Dec. 1938
    - "Freedom in the Market Place," Washington Cathedral, Washington, D.C., correspondence, 11 Dec. 1938
    - "The University of Tomorrow," Columbia Alumni Club of Los Angeles, Los Angeles, Calif. 5 Jan. 1939
    - "Should Educators Declare War?" Columbia University Alumni Club of Essex County, N.J., correspondence, 2 Mar. 1939
      - Dennis, William Cullen
      - Dodge, M. Hartley
      - Ludlow, Louis
      - Myers, William Starr
      - Wasson, R. Gordon
    - "Journalism in the United States," 4 May 1939
    - "What Is Past Is Prologue," service in St. Paul's Chapel, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 15 May 1939
    - "The Arena of Public Opinion," luncheon in honor of Cabot medalists, National Press Club, Washington, D.C., 10 Nov. 1939
    - "The Land of Our Future," First Presbyterian Church, Lambertville, N.J., 1 Dec. 1939
    - "The Internationalism of Christianity," Church Club of New York, New York, N.Y., correspondence, 31 Jan. 1940
    - "Propaganda Blitzkrieg Over the United States," Columbia University Club, New York, N.Y., 9 May 1940
    - "Psalm of Youth," annual chapel service, Graduate School of Journalism, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 14 May 1940
    - "War Propaganda," CBS broadcast, 5 June 1940
    - "Keeping the News Lines Open," 18 Apr. 1941 (Box 162)
    - "The Freedom of Printing," CBS broadcast, 6 May 1941
    - Remarks at luncheon in honor of the 175th anniversary of the opening of St. Paul's Chapel, Bankers' Club, New York, N.Y., 30 Oct. 1941
    - Address to Rotary Club of Buenos Aires, Argentina, 28 Jan. 1942
    - "Will Our Southern Flank Become a Southern Front?"
      - Kiwanis Clubs of Lambertville, N.J., and Doylestown, Pa., 31 Mar. 1942
    - "Watchmen! Be Clear and Accurate!" service, St. Paul's Chapel, Graduate School of Journalism, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 11 May 1942
    - Address at farmer-businessmen's picnic, Hunterdon County, N.J., 24 June 1942
    - "Freezing the Press," Fourth Accounting Institute banquet, New York, N.Y., 20 Oct. 1942
      - Correspondence and clipping book
        - Bickel, Karl A.
        - Castle, William R.
        - Cooper, Kent
        - Hoover, Herbert
        - Landon, Alfred M.
        - Moore, John Bassett
      - Clipping book (Box 163)
    - "The Relation of News to Global Peace," Haverford College, Haverford, Pa., 12 Jan. 1943
    - Address at memorial service for Alexander Woollcott, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 28 Jan. 1943
    - "A Salute to Reporters of War," annual chapel service, Graduate School of Journalism, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 10 May 1943
    - "The Mobilization of Civilian Brain Power," Earlham College, Richmond, Ind., 21 June 1943
    - "Welcome to New York," luncheon in honor of six visiting Latin American journalists, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 13 Apr. 1944 (Box 164)
    - "On the Eve of Invasion," chapel service, Graduate School of Journalism, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 8 May 1944
    - "The Education of a Hemisphere," University of Havana, Havana, Cuba, 15 July 1944
    - Talk to students before embarking on world trip, Graduate School of Journalism, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 5 Jan. 1945
    - Radio interview concerning American Society of Newspaper Editors, World Free Press Mission, Chungking, China, 30 Mar. 1945
    - Radio broadcast to Japanese journalists, Manila, Philippines, 27 Apr. 1945
    - Radio broadcast, Philippine Hour, Manila, Philippines, 29 Apr. 1945
    - "The Big Four in the News World," Flag Day exercises, Sons of the Revolution in the State of New York, 14 June 1945
    - Remarks, American Society of Newspaper Editors, annual meeting, Washington, D.C., 20 Apr. 1946
    - Address, 33rd annual chapel service, Graduate School of Journalism, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 17 May 1946
    - "Industrial Journalism, A New Opportunity," E. I. Du Pont de Nemours and Co., Wilmington, Del., 25 June 1946
    - "The Need for Leadership," Grace Church, New York, 20 Oct. 1946
    - "Pictures Can Be More Informative Than Type," American Press Institute, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 28 Oct. 1946
    - Remarks, editorial seminar, American Press Institute, 20 Jan. 1947
    - Remarks, Joseph Pulitzer Centennial ceremony, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 10 Apr. 1947
    - Remarks at American Press Institute opening, 5 May 1947
    - "The Foundation for a School of Journalism," Central University of Venezuela, 11 June 1947
    - "The Future of the Press," Association of Army-Navy Chaplains, Governor's Island, N.Y., 8 Mar. 1948
    - Remarks presenting Romulo Gallegos for honorary degree of Doctor of Laws, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 9 July 1948
    - "The Pen Can Be as Mighty as the Sword," 165th anniversary of the birth of Simon Bolivar, 23 July 1948
    - Remarks at dinner for German publishers and editors, Graduate School of Journalism, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 13 Sept. 1948
    - "What Makes a Happy City," American Press Institute, seminar for city editors, 11 Apr. 1949
    - "The Inside of a Newspaper Should Be Like the Inside of the Home," seminar on women's pages, American Press Institute, 6 June 1949
    - Remarks at American Press Institute, seminar on management and goals, 12 Sept. 1949
    - Opening Talk to Students, School of Journalism, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 28 Sept. 1949
    - Remarks at National Conference of Editorial Writers, 20 Oct. 1949
    - Remarks at Maria Moors Cabot convocation, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 11 Nov. 1949
    - Remarks at opening of the Japanese seminar, American Press Institute, 3 Jan. 1950
    - Remarks at American Press Institute, seminar on management and costs, 22 May 1950
    - Address to Austrian journalists, American Press Institute, 2 June 1950
    - "Do Not Be Discouraged," International Press Institute conference, 18 Sept. 1950
    - Remarks at Maria Moors Cabot convocation, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 10 Oct. 1950
    - Radio interview with Robert McKee, "Views of the News," 15 Nov. 1950
    - "The Zeal To Live," University of Brazil, 16 Dec. 1950
    - Remarks on Joseph Pulitzer's 104th birthday, 10 Apr. 1951
    - Remarks at dinner for Grantland Rice, Links Club, New York, N.Y., 1 May 1951
    - "A Sermon on a Mountain," All Saint's Episcopal Church, Leonia, N.J., 20 May 1951
    - Remarks at the Education Writers Association, 28 May 1951
    - Remarks to the Association for Education in Journalism, 26 Aug. 1952
    - Address to the class of 1953, Graduate School of Journalism, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 25 Sept. 1952
    - "The Importance of Contacts," 21 Oct. 1952
    - "What Religion Means to Me," Trinity Church, New York, N.Y., 7 Jan. 1953 (Box 165)
    - Comment on address of Jose Cafe Filho, "A Tribute to the Brazilian Press," Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, 4 Dec. 1954
    - "Life in an Ivory Tower," Overseas Press Club, 24 May 1956
    - "The First Benjamin Franklin Journalism Scholarships," 14 June 1956
    - "The Ivory Towers Are Cracking," undelivered lecture, correspondence, William Bentinck-Smith, 1956
    - "Let's Prepare for the Twenty-first Century," undelivered lecture, outline, 1956
    - "Our Greatest Reservoir of Power," undelivered lecture, outline, 1956
    - "Public Opinion Rules the World," undelivered lecture, outline, 1956
    - Remarks at Dean Ackerman Night, Overseas Press Club, New York, N.Y., 24 Feb. 1959
    - Speech at opening of 50th anniversary celebration, Graduate School of Journalism, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 10 Apr. 1963
    - "Black Markets in News," undated
    - Speeches and lectures, correspondence concerning, 1917-1922, 1939, undated
    - Miscellaneous correspondence concerning lectures, W. Colston, 1956-1957
    - Miscellaneous notes and source material for lectures
    - Speeches and lectures, miscellaneous printed matter
  - Articles (Box 166)
    - "Indiana Girl, Sculptor for John D. Rockefeller, Confirms Fairy Story of East," Indianapolis Sunday Star, 12 Jan. 1913
    - Articles for the New York Press, Mar.-May 1913
    - "Reviving the Land Bank in America," Feb. 1914
    - Articles for the United Press, Berlin, Mar. 1915-Dec. 1916
    - Message to Indiana City Editors' Association, Richmond Palladium, Richmond, Ind., 15 July 1916
    - Articles for the United Press, Berlin, Germany
      - Jan.-Feb. 1917, undated
      - Mar. 1915-May 1916, scrapbooks (Box 167)
    - Articles for Le Journal, Paris, France, Feb. 1917
    - Articles for New York Tribune syndicate, Feb.-June 1917, undated
    - "What's the Matter with Germany?" Independent, 28 Apr. 1917
    - "What Wartime Germany Does with Printers' Ink," Pep, June 1917
    - Articles for Saturday Evening Post, 1917-1923, (bound vol.) (Box 168)
    - "The Bernhardi of the Seas," Saturday Evening Post, 2 June 1917 (Box 169)
    - "What Is New Orientation?" Saturday Evening Post, 9 June 1917
    - "The Men Who Made Militarism," The Independent, 16 June 1917
    - "The Kaiser and the Blackbird," Saturday Evening Post, 16 June 1917
    - "Kaiser Must Go and Germany Be a Republic before War Can End," New York World, 24 June 1917